Guide to the Time Inc. Time Annotated Bound Issues 1933-2002 MS 3009-RG 38
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Time Annotated Bound Issues
1933-2002
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 38
49 Linear feet (250 volumes)
The record group consists of 249 volumes of bound issues of Time magazine (1933-1934, 1940-2002) and one volume of Letters magazine (1934-1937). The issues of Time are noted as "marked" copies because they include annotations on various articles, primarily the initials of the writer, editor and researcher of the piece. The annotations also include brief observations on various matters of style, word choice, and the like, and paper inserts with count lists of international editions and other information.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Arrangement
The volumes are in chronological order.
Scope and Contents
The record group consists of 249 volumes of bound issues of Time magazine (1933-1934, 1940-2002) and one volume of Letters magazine (1934-1937).
These issues of Time are noted as "marked" copies and were maintained by the Time Inc. Copy Desk. They include annotations on various articles, primarily the initials of the writer, editor and researcher of the piece. Bylines in Time did not become common until the mid-to-late 1970s. Consequently, these bound volumes are the only reliable key to who wrote, researched and edited articles from the pre-byline era, as well as to unattributed articles in later issues. For example, these volumes have been used to attribute works without bylines to noted author James Agee. The annotations also include brief observations on various matters of style, word choice, and the like. The annotations on these post-production issues do not necessarily include substantive editorial choices or changes.
The volumes also include editorial inserts at some points. Some of these were on small slips of paper pinned to a page (when found during processing, pins were removed and the slips clipped to the pages). In the late 1970s, these inserts commonly list stories and their associated writer, editor and researcher for each issue of Time. Also in the late 1970s, "count lists for the international edition" begin to appear.
The record group has some gaps in coverage. There are no issues here of Time from prior to 1933 and from 1935-1939. The volumes for January-March 1946 and April-June 1960 are missing. Also, not all of the issues in the volumes are annotated.
The volume of Letters magazine, consisting of letters to the editor, is not annotated.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Corporate libraries -- New York (State) -- New York.; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Library resources; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- Letters, 1934 October-1937 September [annotated], 1934-1937; 227188 (Offsite-box 1, Volume 1)
- Time, 1933 January-June [annotated], 227187 (Offsite-box 1, Volume 1933.1)
- Time, 1933 July-December [annotated], 227186 (Offsite-box 1, Volume 1933.2)
- Time, 1934 January-June [annotated], 227185 (Offsite-box 2, Volume 1934.1)
- Time, 1934 July-December [annotated], 227184 (Offsite-box 2, Volume 1934.2)
- Time, 1940 January-June [annotated] (Offsite-box 3, Volume 1940.1)
- Time, 1940 July-December [annotated] (Offsite-box 3, Volume 1940.2)
- Time, 1941 January-June [annotated] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 1941.1)
- Time, 1941 July-December [annotated] (Offsite-box 4, Volume 1941.2)
- Time, 1942 January-March [annotated] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 1942.1)
- Time, 1942 April-June [annotated] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 1942.2)
- Time, 1942 July-September [annotated] (Offsite-box 5, Volume 1942.3)
- Time, 1942 October-December [annotated] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 1942.4)
- Time, 1943 January-March [annotated] (Offsite-box 6, Volume 1943.1)
- Time, 1943 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1943.2)
- Time, 1943 July-December [annotated] (Volume 1943.3)
- Time, 1944 January-June [annotated] (Volume 1944.1)
- Time, 1944 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1944.2)
- Time, 1944 July-September (Volume 1944.3)
- Time, 1944 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1944.4)
- Time, 1945 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1945.1)
- Time, 1945 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1945.2)
- Time, 1945 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1945.3)
- Time, 1945 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1945.4)
- TIme, 1946 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1946.2)
- TIme, 1946 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1946.3)
- TIme, 1946 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1946.4)
- TIme, 1947 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1947.1)
- TIme, 1947 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1947.2)
- TIme, 1947 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1947.3)
- TIme, 1947 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1947.4)
- TIme, 1948 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1948.1)
- Time, 1948 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1948.2)
- Time, 1948 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1948.3)
- Time, 1948 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1948.4)
- Time, 1949 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1949.1)
- Time, 1949 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1949.2)
- Time, 1949 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1949.3)
- Time, 1949 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1949.4)
- Time, 1950 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1950.1)
- Time, 1950 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1950.2)
- Time, 1950 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1950.3)
- Time, 1950 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1950.4)
- Time, 1951 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1951.1)
- Time, 1951 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1951.2)
- Time, 1951 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1951.3)
- Time, 1951 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1951.4)
- Time, 1952 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1952.1)
- Time, 1952 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1952.2)
- Time, 1952 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1952.3)
- Time, 1952 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1952.4)
- Time, 1953 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1953.1)
- Time, 1953 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1953.2)
- Time, 1953 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1953.3)
- Time, 1953 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1953.4)
- Time, 1954 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1954.1)
- Time, 1954 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1954.2)
- Time, 1954 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1954.3)
- Time, 1954 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1954.4)
- Time, 1955 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1955.1)
- Time, 1955 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1955.2)
- Time, 1955 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1955.3)
- Time, 1955 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1955.4)
- Time, 1956 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1956.1)
- Time, 1956 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1956.2)
- Time, 1956 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1956.3)
- Time, 1956 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1956.4)
- Time, 1957 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1957.1)
- Time, 1957 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1957.2)
- Time, 1957 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1957.3)
- Time, 1957 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1957.4)
- Time, 1958 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1958.1)
- Time, 1958 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1958.2)
- Time, 1958 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1958.3)
- Time, 1958 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1958.4)
- Time, 1959 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1959.1)
- Time, 1959 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1959.2)
- Time, 1959 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1959.3)
- Time, 1959 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1959.4)
- Time, 1960 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1960.1)
- Time, 1960 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1960.3)
- Time, 1960 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1960.4)
- Time, 1961 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1961.1)
- Time, 1961 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1961.2)
- Time, 1961 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1961.3)
- Time, 1961 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1961.4)
- Time, 1962 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1962.1)
- Time, 1962 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1962.2)
- Time, 1962 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1962.3)
- Time, 1962 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1962.4)
- Time, 1963 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1963.1)
- Time, 1963 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1963.2)
- Time, 1963 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1963.3)
- Time, 1963 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1963.4)
- Time, 1964 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1964.1)
- Time, 1964 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1964.2)
- Time, 1964 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1964.3)
- Time, 1964 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1964.4)
- Time, 1965 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1965.1)
- Time, 1965 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1965.2)
- Time, 1965 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1965.3)
- Time, 1965 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1965.4)
- Time, 1966 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1966.1)
- Time, 1966 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1966.2)
- Time, 1966 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1966.3)
- Time, 1966 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1966.4)
- Time, 1967 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1967.1)
- Time, 1967 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1967.2)
- Time, 1967 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1967.3)
- Time, 1967 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1967.4)
- Time, 1968 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1968.1)
- Time, 1968 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1968.2)
- Time, 1968 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1968.3)
- Time, 1968 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1968.4)
- Time, 1969 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1969.1)
- Time, 1969 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1969.2)
- Time, 1969 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1969.3)
- Time, 1969 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1969.4)
- Time, 1970 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1970.1)
- Time, 1970 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1970.2)
- Time, 1970 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1970.3)
- Time, 1970 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1970.4)
- Time, 1971 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1971.1)
- Time, 1971 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1971.2)
- Time, 1971 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1971.3)
- Time, 1971 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1971.4)
- Time, 1972 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1972.1)
- Time, 1972 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1972.2)
- Time, 1972 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1972.3)
- Time, 1972 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1972.4)
- Time, 1973 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1973.1)
- Time, 1973 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1973.2)
- Time, 1973 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1973.3)
- Time, 1973 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1973.4)
- Time, 1974 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1974.1)
- Time, 1974 April-June 1974[annotated] (Volume 1974.2)
- Time, 1974 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1974.3)
- Time, 1974 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1974.4)
- Time, 1975 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1975.1)
- Time, 1975 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1975.2)
- Time, 1975 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1975.3)
- Time, 1975 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1975.4)
- Time, 1976 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1976.1)
- Time, 1976 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1976.2)
- Time, 1976 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1976.3)
- Time, 1976 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1976.4)
- Time, 1977 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1977.1)
- Time, 1977 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1977.2)
- Time, 1977 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1977.3)
- Time, 1977 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1977.4)
- Time, 1978 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1978.1)
- Time, 1978 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1978.2)
- Time, 1978 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1978.3)
- Time, 1978 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1978.4)
- Time, 1979 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1979.1)
- Time, 1979 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1979.2)
- Time, 1979 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1979.3)
- Time, 1979 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1979.4)
- Time, 1980 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1980.1)
- Time, 1980 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1980.2)
- Time, 1980 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1980.3)
- Time, 1980 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1980.4)
- Time, 1981 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1981.1)
- Time, 1981 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1981.2)
- Time, 1981 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1981.3)
- Time, 1981 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1981.4)
- Time, 1982 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1982.1)
- Time, 1982 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1982.2)
- Time, 1982 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1982.3)
- Time, 1982 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1982.4)
- Time, 1983 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1983.1)
- Time, 1983 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1983.2)
- Time, 1983 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1983.3)
- Time, 1983 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1983.4)
- Time, 1984 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1984.1)
- Time, 1984 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1984.2)
- Time, 1984 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1984.3)
- Time, 1984 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1984.4)
- Time, 1985 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1985.1)
- Time, 1985 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1985.2)
- Time, 1985 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1985.3)
- Time, 1985 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1985.4)
- Time, 1986 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1986.1)
- Time, 1986 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1986.2)
- Time, 1986 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1986.3)
- Time, 1986 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1986.4)
- Time, 1987 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1987.1)
- Time, 1987 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1987.2)
- Time, 1987 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1987.3)
- Time, 1987 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1987.4)
- Time, 1988 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1988.1)
- Time, 1988 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1988.2)
- Time, 1988 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1988.3)
- Time, 1988 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1988.4)
- Time, 1989 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1989.1)
- Time, 1989 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1989.2)
- Time, 1989 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1989.3)
- Time, 1989 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1989.4)
- Time, 1990 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1990.1)
- Time, 1990 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1990.2)
- Time, 1990 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1990.3)
- Time, 1990 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1990.4)
- Time, 1991 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1991.1)
- Time, 1991 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1991.2)
- Time, 1991 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1991.3)
- Time, 1991 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1991.4)
- Time, 1992 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1992.1)
- Time, 1992 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1992.2)
- Time, 1992 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1992.3)
- Time, 1992 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1992.4)
- Time, 1993 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1993.1)
- Time, 1993 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1993.2)
- Time, 1993 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1993.3)
- Time, 1993 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1993.4)
- Time, 1994 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1994.1)
- Time, 1994 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1994.2)
- Time, 1994 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1994.3)
- Time, 1994 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1994.4)
- Time, 1995 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1995.1)
- Time, 1995 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1995.2)
- Time, 1995 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1995.3)
- Time, 1995 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1995.4)
- Time, 1996 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1996.1)
- Time, 1996 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1996.2)
- Time, 1996 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1996.3)
- Time, 1996 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1996.4)
- Time, 1997 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1997.1)
- Time, 1997 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1997.2)
- Time, 1997 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1997.3)
- Time, 1997 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1997.4)
- Time, 1998 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1998.1)
- Time, 1998 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1998.2)
- Time, 1998 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1998.3)
- Time, 1998 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1998.4)
- Time, 1999 January-March [annotated] (Volume 1999.1)
- Time, 1999 April-June [annotated] (Volume 1999.2)
- Time, 1999 July-September [annotated] (Volume 1999.3)
- Time, 1999 October-December [annotated] (Volume 1999.4)
- Time, 2000 January-March [annotated] (Volume 2000.1)
- Time, 2000 April-June [annotated] (Volume 2000.2)
- Time, 2000 July-September [annotated] (Volume 2000.3)
- Time, 2000 October-December [annotated] (Volume 2000.4)
- Time, 2001 January-March [annotated] (Volume 2001.1)
- Time, 2001 April-June [annotated] (Volume 2001.2)
- Time, 2001 July-September [annotated] (Volume 2001.3)
- Time, 2001 October-December [annotated] (Volume 2001.4)
- Time, 2002 January-March [annotated] (Volume 2002.1)
- Time, 2002 April-June [annotated] (Volume 2002.2)
- Time, 2002 July-September [annotated] (Volume 2002.3)
- Time, 2002 October-December [annotated] (Volume 2002.4)